<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>vuejs on Adam Cowley | Full Stack Development Lead specialising in Neo4j and Node JS</title>
    <link>http://www.adamcowley.co.uk/tags/vuejs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in vuejs on Adam Cowley | Full Stack Development Lead specialising in Neo4j and Node JS</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 14:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.adamcowley.co.uk/tags/vuejs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Multi-tenant SaaS Control Panel for Neo4j Desktop</title>
      <link>http://www.adamcowley.co.uk/neo4j/sass-control-panel-graph-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.adamcowley.co.uk/neo4j/sass-control-panel-graph-app/</guid>
      <description>The introduction of multi-database in Neo4j 4.0 has certainly made the lives of aspiring SaaS vendors. Previously to 4.0, it was only possible to run one instance of a Neo4j database on a server at any time. This meant a lot of effort around standing up Neo4j instances for customers of SaaS services. Now, it&amp;rsquo;s as simple as running a CREATE DATABASE command against the system database.
The Scenario So, let&amp;rsquo;s paint a scenario.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Real-Time UI on top of Neo4j with Vue.js and Kafka</title>
      <link>http://www.adamcowley.co.uk/neo4j/real-time-ui-vuejs-neo4j-kafka/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 12:55:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.adamcowley.co.uk/neo4j/real-time-ui-vuejs-neo4j-kafka/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I will demonstrate how you can build a real-time application on top of Neo4j using a few open source plugins. Due to brevity, this will only be a basic application but you can take the principles and make it as complicated as you need.
For this example, I will also be using Vue.js on top of an express server communicating through websockets. If you prefer something like React then it will work just as well.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>